<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Anchore Engine – Image Analysis Process</title><link>/docs/general/concepts/images/analysis/</link><description>Recent Hugo news from gohugo.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><image><url>img/hugo.png</url><title>GoHugo.io</title><link>/docs/general/concepts/images/analysis/</link></image><atom:link href="/docs/general/concepts/images/analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Malware Scanning</title><link>/docs/general/concepts/images/analysis/malware_scanning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/general/concepts/images/analysis/malware_scanning/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Anchore Engine now supports the use of the open-source &lt;a href="https://clamav.net">ClamAV&lt;/a> malware scanner to detect malicious code embedded in container images.
This scan occurs only at analysis time when the image content itself is available, and the scan results are available via the Engine API as well as for consumption
in new policy gates to allow gating of image with malware findings.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="signature-db-updates">Signature DB Updates&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Each analyzer service will run a malware signature update before analyzing each image. This does add some latency to the overall analysis time but ensures the signatures
are as up-to-date as possible for each image analyzed. The update behavior can be disabled if you prefer to manage the freshness of the db via another route, such as a shared filesystem
mounted to all analyzer nodes that is updated on a schedule. See the configuration section for details on disabling the db update.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The status of the db update is present in each scan output for each image.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="scan-results">Scan Results&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;code>malware&lt;/code> content type is a list of scan results. Each result is the run of a malware scanner, by default &lt;code>clamav&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The list of files found to contain malware signature matches is in the &lt;code>findings&lt;/code> property of each scan result. An empty array value indicates no matches found.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;code>metadata&lt;/code> property provides generic metadata specific to the scanner. For the ClamAV implementation, this includes the version data about the signature db used and
if the db update was enabled during the scan. If the db update is disabled, then the &lt;code>db_version&lt;/code> property of the metadata will not have values since the only way to get
the version metadata is during a db update.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>{
&amp;quot;content&amp;quot;: [
{
&amp;quot;findings&amp;quot;: [
{
&amp;quot;path&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;/somebadfile&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;signature&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Unix.Trojan.MSShellcode-40&amp;quot;
},
{
&amp;quot;path&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;/somedir/somepath/otherbadfile&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;signature&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Unix.Trojan.MSShellcode-40&amp;quot;
}
],
&amp;quot;metadata&amp;quot;: {
&amp;quot;db_update_enabled&amp;quot;: true,
&amp;quot;db_version&amp;quot;: {
&amp;quot;bytecode&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;331&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;daily&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;25890&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;main&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;59&amp;quot;
}
},
&amp;quot;scanner&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;clamav&amp;quot;
}
],
&amp;quot;content_type&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;malware&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;imageDigest&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;sha256:0eb874fcad5414762a2ca5b2496db5291aad7d3b737700d05e45af43bad3ce4d&amp;quot;
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;h2 id="policy-rules">Policy Rules&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A policy gate called &lt;code>malware&lt;/code> is available with a &lt;code>scans&lt;/code> trigger that will fire for each file and signature combination found in the image so that you can fail an evaluation of an image
if malware was detected during the analysis scan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See &lt;a href="/docs/usage/cli_usage/policies/policy_checks/">policy checks&lt;/a> for more details&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Content Hints</title><link>/docs/general/concepts/images/analysis/content_hints/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/general/concepts/images/analysis/content_hints/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Anchore Engine includes the ability to read a user-supplied &amp;lsquo;hints&amp;rsquo; file to allow users to override and/or augment the software artifacts that are
discovered by Anchore during its image analysis process. The hints file, if present, contains records that describe a software package characteristics explicitly,
and are then added to the software bill of materials (SBOM). For example, if the owner of a CI/CD container build process knows that there are some
software packages installed explicitly in a container image, but Anchore&amp;rsquo;s regular analyzers are either not discovering the software or the analysis of the software
package is incomplete, this mechanism can be used to include that information in the image&amp;rsquo;s SBOM, exactly as if the package were discovered normally.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="configuration">Configuration&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>See &lt;a href="/docs/install/configuration/content_hints/">Configuring Content Hints&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once enabled, the analyzer services will look for a file with a specific name, location and format located within the container image - &lt;code>/anchore_hints.json&lt;/code>.&lt;br>
The format of the file is illustrated using some examples, below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="os-package-records">OS Package Records&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>OS Packages are those that will represent packages installed using OS / Distro style package managers. Currently supported package types are &lt;code>rpm, dpkg, apkg&lt;/code>
for RedHat, Debian, and Alpine flavored package managers respectively. Note that, for OS Packages, the name of the package is unique per SBOM, meaning
that only one package named &amp;lsquo;somepackage&amp;rsquo; can exist in an image&amp;rsquo;s SBOM, and specifying a name in the hints file that conflicts with one with the same name
discovered by the Anchore analyzers will result in the record from the hints file taking precedence (override).&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Minimum required values for a package record in anchore_hints.json&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> {
&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;musl&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;version&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;1.1.20-r8&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;apkg&amp;quot;
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Complete record demonstrating all of the available characteristics of a software package that can be specified&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> {
&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;musl&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;version&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;1.1.20&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;release&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;r8&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;origin&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Timo Ter\u00e4s &amp;lt;timo.teras@iki.fi&amp;gt;&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;license&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;MIT&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;size&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;61440&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;source&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;musl&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;files&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;/lib/ld-musl-x86_64.so.1&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;/lib/libc.musl-x86_64.so.1&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;/lib&amp;quot;],
&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;apkg&amp;quot;
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;h3 id="non-oslanguage-package-records">Non-OS/Language Package Records&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Non-OS / language package records are similar in form to the OS package records, but with some extra/different characteristics being supplied, namely
the &lt;code>location&lt;/code> field. Since multiple non-os packages can be installed that have the same name, the location field is particularly important as it
is used to distinguish between package records that might otherwise be identical. Valid types for non-os packages are currently &lt;code>java, python, gem, npm, nuget, go, binary&lt;/code>.&lt;br>
For the latest types that are available, see the &lt;code>anchore-cli image content &amp;lt;someimage&amp;gt;&lt;/code> output, which lists available types for any given deployment of Anchore Engine.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Minimum required values for a package record in anchore_hints.json&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> {
&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;wicked&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;version&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;0.6.1&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;gem&amp;quot;
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Complete record demonstrating all of the available characteristics of a software package that can be specified&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> {
&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;wicked&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;version&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;0.6.1&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;location&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;/app/gems/specifications/wicked-0.9.0.gemspec&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;origin&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;schneems&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;license&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;MIT&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;source&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;http://github.com/schneems/wicked&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;files&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;README.md&amp;quot;],
&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;gem&amp;quot;
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;h3 id="putting-it-all-together">Putting it all together&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Using the above examples, a complete anchore_hints.json file, when discovered by Anchore Engine located in &lt;code>/anchore_hints.json&lt;/code> inside any container image, is provided here:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>{
&amp;quot;packages&amp;quot;: [
{
&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;musl&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;version&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;1.1.20-r8&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;apkg&amp;quot;
},
{
&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;wicked&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;version&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;0.6.1&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;gem&amp;quot;
}
]
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>With such a hints file in an image based for example on &lt;code>alpine:latest&lt;/code>, the resulting image content would report these two package/version records
as part of the SBOM for the analyzed image, when viewed using &lt;code>anchore-cli image content &amp;lt;image&amp;gt; os&lt;/code> and &lt;code>anchore-cli image content &amp;lt;image&amp;gt; gem&lt;/code>
to view the &lt;code>musl&lt;/code> and &lt;code>wicked&lt;/code> package records, respectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="note-about-using-the-hints-file-feature">Note about using the hints file feature&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>The hints file feature is disabled by default, and is meant to be used in very specific circumstances where a trusted entity is entrusted with creating
and installing, or removing an anchore_hints.json file from all containers being built. It is not meant to be enabled when the container image builds
are not explicitly controlled, as the entity that is building container images could override any SBOM entry that Anchore would normally discover, which
affects the vulnerability/policy status of an image. For this reason, the feature is disabled by default and must be explicitly enabled in configuration
only if appropriate for your use case .&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>